Contact

tracy.r.carroll@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/tracy-j-carroll-msn-rn-ne-bc-cmsrn-4479ab56 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing

Critical Care

Hospitals

Languages

English

Certifications

Lean Six Sigma Blue Belt Certification

Certified Medical Surgery Registered Nurse

Nurse Executive

Honors-Awards

North Carolina Nurses Association Best Practices Award - Caring for Ourselves

#1 Unit for HCAHPS Scores 9-10 in FY16

Nurse Manager of the Year

#1 unit for HCAHPS scores 9-10 in FY15

Nurse Executive Leadership Conference: Frances Ross Memorial Scholarship recipient

Publications

Recognition A Key Retention Strategy for the Mature Nurse

Reducing liver transplant length of stay: a Lean Six Sigma approach

Preparing for Electronic Medical Record Implementation: Carolina Care Communication in an Electronic Environment

Tracy J. Carroll, MSN, RN, NE-BC, CMSRN

Director, Inpatient Heart & Vascular Services at UNC Health Care Chapel Hill, North Carolina

Summary

Experienced professional with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Skilled in Management, Health Care, and Nursing. Strong operations professional with a MSN focused in Health Care Systems Administration from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill.

Experience

UNC School of Nursing
Adjunct Faculty Instructor
January 2019 - Present (1 year 6 months)
Chapel Hill, NC

UNC Health Care

19 years 1 month

Director, Inpatient Heart & Vascular Services October 2016 - Present (3 years 9 months)

This position provides leadership for the Heart & Vascular Inpatient Units and Adult Specialty Care Areas. The Heart & Vascular Inpatient Service is comprised of 72 inpatient beds and four specialty care services. Physician services housed throughout these inpatient units include: general cardiology, procedural cardiology (interventional and electrophysiology), heart failure, cardiac surgery, thoracic surgery and vascular surgery. The Specialty Care areas include Cardiac Surveillance, Adult Venous Access Team, Adult Specialty Care Team and Adult Rapid Response Team. Additionally, the Heart & Vascular service supports the organizational efforts to maintain Chest Pain Center Accreditation, established in April 2014.

Patient Services Manager III

November 2014 - November 2016 (2 years 1 month)

Wound, Ostomy, Continence Nurse Consult Service

Directly supervise and support Wound, Ostomy, Continence Nurses (9 employees) who provide consultation to patients throughout the organization

Patient Services Manager III
March 2011 - October 2016 (5 years 8 months)

Directly supervise and support Registered Nurses, Nursing Assistants, Health Unit Coordinators, and Clinical Support Technicians (45+ employees) on a 15-bed acute care medical-surgical unit specializing in pre/post liver and kidney transplants as well as high-risk plastic surgery, urology, and ophthalmology.

Clinical Nurse IV April 2008 - March 2011 (3 years)

- 3 Anderson/ICCU
- Directly supervise and support Registered Nurses, Nursing Assistants, Health Unit Coordinators, and Telemetry Technicians (90+ employees) on a 29-bed intermediate medical cardiology unit.
- Assist with unit management including: KRONOS, annual PREP evaluations,
 Hiring for Excellence, orientation of new staff, staff education, and Carolina
 Care.
- Provide care for clinically complex patients and their families with cardiac diagnoses including physical assessment, intervention, medication administration, education and emotional support.
- Chair of the UNC Health Care shared governance Nursing Professional Development Council.
- Chair of the Critical Care CN IV Leadership Team.
- Sole UNCH Staff Nurse Representative Member on the Magnet Steering Committee.
- Instructor for Critical Care Odyssey and Critical Care Expo.
- Interim Nurse Manager (July 2009-October 2009 and October 2010-January 2011).

Clinical Nurse III
February 2005 - March 2008 (3 years 2 months)
3 Anderson/ICCU

- Provide care for clinically complex patients and their families with cardiac diagnoses including physical assessment, intervention, medication administration, education and emotional support.
- Supported the unit through staff education and participation in unit/hospital committees including: 3 Anderson Clinical Practice Committee, Skin/Wound Resource Team, Co-chair of the UNC Health Care Shared Governance Nursing Professional Development Council, and Chair of the Heart Center Professional Development Committee.

Clinical Nurse II
July 2003 - February 2005 (1 year 8 months)
3 Anderson/ICCU

Clinical Nurse I July 2002 - July 2003 (1 year 1 month) 3 Anderson/ICCU

Nursing Assistant June 2001 - July 2002 (1 year 2 months) 6 Women's

Education

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill MSN, Health Care Systems Administration · (2012 - 2015)

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Bachelor's degree, Nursing · (2000 - 2002)

Wake Forest University
Bachelor's degree, Health & Exercise Science · (1995 - 1999)